# **Reuben Heller** reubenheller@gmail.com / 07814 014030

An established and unflappable freelance strategist. I've worked at many leading creative agencies (e.g. AKQA, Publicis Sapient, Karmarama) on a range of forward-thinking clients (e.g. Barclays, VW, BBC). I have experience in virtually every sector but I have particular knowledge of financial services, tech and media. All this means I can slot easily into your existing team, turn pitches/projects around quickly and represent your agency well in front of senior clients.

Areas of Expertise: Market analysis, qualitative research, campaign development & digital strategy.

### **Experience**

2005-date	Freelance Strategy Director, Karmarama, AKQA, Wunderman Thompson and others
2003-05	Senior Strategist, AKQA: Strategy lead on Sainsbury's
2001-03	Digital Planner, Publicis: Accounts including HP and United Biscuits

### **Recent Projects**

### Client: Starling / Agency: Karmarama

Worked with Starling, a new banking brand, to help determine their positioning prior to launch. This involved landscape/competitor analysis and consumer research covering issues such as desired features, and barriers to trusting an app-only bank.

## Client: Shell / Agency: Wunderman Thompson

Shell was looking to reengineer its fleet loyalty scheme. To engage drivers, I worked on a strategy involving an app-based loyalty scheme and a new CRM programme. For fleet managers, we came up with a suite of tools to help them understand their fleet's performance.

### Client: Airline / Agency: Digital Consulting Agency

Helped deliver a successful pitch for an airline seeking to increase its direct sales. My strategy was to create differentiation by giving direct customers a premium customer experience over those buying via third parties. This helped the airline get out of the trenches of competing solely on price.

### Client: Mitie / Agency: AML

Developed a new positioning for the security division of Mitie, a facilities management and professional services company. This involved market analysis, creating customer personas, stakeholder interviews and running workshops to ensure internal buy-in for the new positioning.

### Client: Barclays / Agency: Drum

Developed an overarching social strategy for Barclays. This involved auditing its existing social channels and content, creating consumer personas and working with internal stakeholders to understand their needs and the practicalities of content creation.

#### **Education**

- MSc Marketing, Manchester Business School, '96 '97
- LLB (Hons) Law, 2.1, Birmingham University, '92 '95